Previously on the show.
Episode sebelumnya.
To find the rainbow beans, Weslie and friends
Demi dapat kacang pelangi, Weslie dan teman-teman
took part in the Rainbow Festival contest.
ikut dalam kontes Festival Pelangi.
In the rainbow labyrinth, they came close
Di labirin pelangi, mereka nyaris bertemu Tibbie beberapa kali.
The rainbow festival contest is not over yet.
Kontes festival pelangi belum selesai.
When will they finally see each other?
Kapan mereka akan saling bertemu?
"Flying Island: The Sky Adventure: Race to Complete the Rainbow Puzzle."
Petualangan Langit Pulau Terbang: Berlomba Menyelesaikan Teka-Teki Pelangi.
So many people! I wonder if Tibbie'll be here.
Banyak orang! Aku penasaran apa Tibbie ada di sini.
Weslie, I'm so nervous!
Weslie, aku amat gugup!
You don't look nervous at all.
Kau tampak tidak gugup.
I'm eating because I'm nervous.
Aku sedang makan karena gugup.
Hello, competitors. I am your host today.
Halo, Pesaing. Aku pewara untuk hari ini.
Welcome to the venue for the rainbow puzzle contest.
Selamat datang di kontes teka-teki pelangi.
Let me explain the rules for this competition.
Biar kujelaskan aturan kompetisi ini.
First, find the nine puzzle pieces hidden in the city,
Pertama, temukan sembilan teka-teki yang tersembunyi di kota,
then piece them together correctly.
lalu satukan semuanya dengan benar.
One of the puzzle pieces is one of a kind.
Salah satu keping teka-tekinya unik.
First one to finish the puzzle will win our mystery prize.
Yang pertama selesaikan teka-teki akan memenangkan hadiah misteri kita.
I must win this time to get the prize for Wolnie.
Kini aku harus menang agar dapat hadiah untuk Wolnie.
Lastly, I would like to remind everyone
Terakhir, aku mau mengingatkan semua orang...
that some boxes do not have puzzle pieces inside.
bahwa beberapa kotak tak berisi keping teka-teki.
If you are unlucky, there will be small penalties.
Jika kau sial, akan ada hukuman kecil.
Everyone must be careful.
Semua harus berhati-hati.
The contest has now officially begun.
Kontesnya kini resmi dimulai.
Such a big city. Where should we go to find puzzle pieces?
Kota ini besar. Harus cari kepingnya ke mana?
Be patient, Paddi.
Sabar, Paddi.
Searching like this is way too hard. Look at my skills.
Mencari seperti ini terlalu sulit. Lihat kemampuanku.
I found a box.
Aku dapat kotak.
Quick, open it.
Cepat buka!
It's a fake one.
Itu kotak palsu.
Weslie, I'm tired. We should take a break.
Weslie, aku lelah. Kita harus istirahat.
There's another box.
Ada kotak lainnya.
I'll bring it down. Let's see.
Aku akan ambil. Mari kita lihat.
Could it be another fake?
Apakah kotak palsu lagi?
We'll know when we open it.
Kita akan tahu saat buka.
It's that one-of-a-kind puzzle piece.
Ini kepingan teka-teki unik.
Who knew we could find pieces while trying to sleep?
Siapa duga dapat ini saat mau tidur?
Paddi, let's split up to find the other pieces.
Paddi, mari berpencar untuk mencari bagian lain.
We'll finish the mission faster that way.
Kita bisa selesaikan misinya lebih cepat.
Okay.
Baiklah.
I knew Green Bean would hide the pieces here.
Aku tahu Kacang Hijau akan sembunyikan di sini.
Red Bean, aren't you a referee?
Kacang Merah, bukankah kau wasit?
Why would you be looking for pieces?
Kenapa kau mencari kepingannya?
Why can't I find any pieces anywhere?
Kenapa tak ada kepingan di mana pun?
Wait, you there. You were too careless.
Tunggu. Kau terlalu ceroboh.
You dropped this just now.
Kau baru saja menjatuhkan ini.
I dropped this?
Aku menjatuhkan ini?
Puzzle pieces? But these pieces...
Kepingan teka-teki? Tapi kepingan ini…
I hid them so well. There's no way they will find them.
Aku sembunyikan dengan baik. Tak mungkin bisa ditemukan.
Isn't it because I picked the best places?
Bukankah karena kupilih tempat terbaik?
I thought of them first.
- Aku yang pertama pikirkan. - Itu aku.
No more fighting. Let's go find the captain and she can tell us.
Hentikan. Cari kapten dan dia bisa beri tahu.
Good idea.
Ide bagus.
Why are you copying me?
Kenapa kau meniruku?
You copied me!
- Kau meniruku! - Kalian meniru aku!
Can we really find puzzle pieces
Apa ada kepingan teka-teki
in such a faraway place?
di tempat yang jauh?
Of course. With less competition, it's more likely we'll find something.
Tentu. Makin sedikit saingan, kita lebih mungkin temukan sesuatu.
Oh, that makes sense! I guess that means we'll win!
Benar! Berarti kita akan menang!
After we get the prize, we'll catch the goats too.
Setelah dapat hadiah, kita juga akan menangkap kambing.
Dad, what is that?
Ayah, apa itu?
It's a puzzle piece box.
Ini kotak teka-teki.
Quick, open it!
Baik, buka!
Argh, it's fake!
Ini palsu!
Wolffy, this isn't what you said it would be!
Wolffy, ini bukan seperti katamu tadi!
Wolnie, calm down!
Wolnie, tenang.
Mom, look!
Ibu, lihat!
There's a door here!
Di sini ada pintu!
It looks a little strange.
Ini agak aneh.
Maybe there are lots of puzzle pieces inside.
Mungkin ada banyak keping teka-teki di dalam.
Wolnie, look at this vase.
Wolnie, lihat vas ini.
It's so artsy. It suits my taste so well!
Sangat artistik. Cocok dengan seleraku!
There's also a couch.
Ada sofa juga.
It gives such a familiar feeling.
Itu semua terasa tak asing.
Wolnie, look at the kid in this photo.
Wolnie, lihat anak di foto ini.
He looks so much like Willie. They're basically identical.
Dia mirip sekali dengan Willie, bahkan identik.
Wolffy, look around carefully.
Wolffy, lihat baik-baik.
Isn't this our room on Sirius?
Ini kamar kita di Sirius?
I didn't expect the main body of Sirius to end up in Rainbow City.
Aku tak menduga bagian utama Sirius berada di Kota Pelangi.
Wolnie, wait here at the house.
Wolnie, tunggu di rumah. Aku akan memenangkan hadiahnya.
Puzzle pieces...
Kepingan teka-teki...
Why is it so hard to open?
Kenapa sulit dibuka?
Another box!
Ada kotak lain.
Awesome, it's a puzzle piece.
Bagus, ini keping asli.
Ugh, searching like this is such a pain. Sirius!
Astaga, mencari begini sungguh menyebalkan. Sirius!
Give me all your puzzle pieces.
Serahkan semua kepinganmu.
Run! Someone is snatching the puzzle pieces!
Lari! Ada yang merebut kepingannya!
I'll surely win this time!
Kini aku pasti menang!
How could Wolffy do this?
Kenapa Wolffy tega sekali?
I'm just missing one piece to finish the puzzle.
Sisa satu bagian untuk selesaikan teka-teki.
This guy has stolen so many pieces. I should follow him.
Dia mencuri banyak kepingan. Aku harus mengikutinya.
The cheater is over there.
Pencurinya ada di sana.
There's no one there.
Tak ada orang di sana.
He was just here.
Dia tadi di sini.
You should hurry and find the pieces.
Kau harus cepat menemukan kepingannya.
It'd be too dangerous if it continued like this.
Berbahaya jika terus begini. Aku harus hentikan Wolffy.
Hurry up and hand over your pieces.
Cepat serahkan kepinganmu.
Wolffy! Do you want the one-of-a-kind piece? I have it here.
Wolffy! Mau kepingan unik? Ada padaku.
Weslie, are you here to hand me the gold medal?
Weslie, kau mau menyerahkan itu kepadaku?
That looks like Paddi.
Itu mirip Paddi.
Paddi, wake up!
Paddi, bangun!
Huh? Wolffy!
Wolffy!
Paddi, come up now!
Paddi, cepat kemari!
I wonder how the contest is going.
Bagaimana dengan kontesnya?
Don't try to run, Weslie.
Jangan lari, Weslie!
This is... Oh no! It's Weslie and the others.
Ini... Gawat! Itu Weslie dan yang lain.
If you're smart, be good and hand over the last piece.
Jika pintar, jangan macam-macam dan serahkan kepingnya.
Gotta catch us first!
Tangkap aku dulu!
Fine, then have a taste of this!
Baiklah, rasakan ini!
You forced me to do this. Walk out with the puzzle piece!
Kau memaksaku melakukan ini. Keluar dengan kepingan teka-tekinya!
Wolffy! Let them go!
Wolffy! Lepaskan mereka!
It's Tibbie!
Itu Tibbie!
Are you also here to give me puzzle pieces?
Kau kemari untuk memberi kepingan?
Restart!
Nyala ulang!
Tibbie, come over here!
Tibbie, kemarilah!
You guys wait and see! You are such bullies!
Tunggu saja dan lihatlah. Kalian adalah perisak!
Wow, what a thrill that was!
Tadi sungguh menegangkan!
Thank goodness Tibbie showed up in time.
Syukurlah Tibbie datang tepat waktu.
Tibbie, so you really were in this city!
Tibbie, kau benar-benar ada di kota ini!
We found Tibbie, so we don't need to compete anymore.
Tibbie ketemu, jadi tak perlu berlomba lagi.
You were competing to find me?
Kau berlomba untuk mencariku?
I won't let you escape this time!
Takkan kubiarkan kau lolos!
Tibbie!
Tibbie!
Everyone, look! It's the captain!
Semuanya, lihat! Itu Kapten.
Go save the captain!
Selamatkan kapten!
Everyone, jump!
Semua, lompat!
Little Beans!
Kacang Kecil!
Wolffy, even if you catch us, there's no way you'll get the pieces.
Wolffy, meski kami tertangkap, kau tak bisa dapat kepingannya!
My puzzle piece!
Teka-tekiku!
I knew I would gain something by following him.
Aku tahu mengikuti dia pasti berguna!
Let's welcome our winners to the stage,
Mari sambut pemenang ke panggung, yang datang dari dasar laut, duo ikan!
Congratulations on winning
Selamat sudah memenangi
all the Rainbow Festival prizes accumulated over the years.
semua hadiah Festival Pelangi selama ini.
So many coupons inside.
Ada banyak sekali kupon.
They are all expired!
Semuanya sudah hangus!
Thanks to me, the captain was saved.
Berkat aku, Kapten selamat.
I clearly contributed the most.
Aku jelas yang paling berkontribusi.
No, I did.
Tidak, aku.
-Me! It was me! -No, it was me!
- Aku! Aku! - Bukan, itu aku.
They got hurt because of me.
Mereka terluka karena aku. Kini aku tak bisa beri tahu mereka.
Then we'll leave after they have recovered from their injuries.
Kita bisa pergi setelah mereka sudah pulih.
Yeah!
Ya!
That'd be great!
Itu bagus!
Captain!
- Kapten! - Terima kasih telah menyelamatkanku.
You're welcome!
Terima kasih kembali!
-The captain thanked me! No, it was me! -Definitely me! No, it was me!
- Kapten terima kasih padaku! - Jelas aku! Aku!
Wolnie, I'm back.
Wolnie, aku kembali.
Where's the prize? Why don't you have the prize with you?
Mana hadiahnya? Kenapa tak bawa hadiah?
Wolnie, I'm sorry. I'll work harder.
Wolnie, maaf. Aku akan bekerja lebih keras.
I want my prize!
Aku mau hadiahku!
I will be back!
Aku akan kembali!
TO BE CONTINUED 2770 DAYS FROM SETTING SAIL
BERSAMBUNG 2.770 HARI SEBELUM PULANG